Good morning!
Emmanuel!
(God With Us – Matthew 1:23)
Thank you.
As the Spirit directs...
You may be seated.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
God talks to us through His Word by His Spirit.
So, where is the Word of God?
Let me see it in your hand - your Bible.
Tell your neighbour, "God talks to us through His Word by His Spirit".
Hallelujah!
[Amen.]
Today we talk about the work of faith.
Hallelujah!
We talk about the work of faith to point you to the Lord.
You cannot please Him without faith.
Hallelujah!
The book of 2 Corinthians.
I will take my reading from chapter 5.
Awaiting the New Body
That means this body is a tent.
The body you are in is a tent.
Chapter 5: "For we know that if the earthly tent we live in is destroyed, we have a building from God,"
I take it again:
"For we know that if the earthly tent we live in is destroyed, we have a building from God,
an eternal house in Heaven, not built by human hands.”
Human hands are not employed.
Let's take a look at verse 7.
“For we live by faith, not by sight.
We are confident, I say, and would prefer to be away from the body and at home with the Lord.
[So we make it our goal to please him], whether we are at home in the body or away from it."
Verse 10:
“For we must all appear before the judgement seat of Christ,
so that each of us may receive what is due us for the things done while in the body, whether good or bad."
THE WORK OF FAITH
Today, we see the work of faith as a risk.
Christians today see the work of faith as a risk.
How can I believe what I can’t see with my eyes?
The work of faith is not a risk but a sure and practical act.
How can I believe what I do not see?
We are used to what we see and feel; what you can see by yourself, perceive and feel.
These are things we are used to.
But for me now to begin to believe in what I do not see...
We see it as a risk.
The work of faith is not a risk but a sure and practical act.
If a person has not received the teaching of the Scriptures,
if you have not been grounded in the Word
or you have not received the promise of the Holy Spirit in your spirit,
forcing yourself to do such acts is indeed a risk.
You must be grounded in the Word.
If you have not been grounded in the Word of God,
there will be nothing in your heart for the Spirit of God to use or remind you of.
One would be empty; the heart would be empty.
Heart means spirit.
When the heart is empty, there is nothing for the Spirit to use.
It is not all up to you, certainly, it is not all up to Him;
your genuineness plus His ability makes it happen.
If you are empty, there is nothing for Him to use.
You must be grounded in the Word.
He uses The Word in our heart.
This is why we give you the "faith bracelet" to meditate.
Meditation in the Word of God is a visit with God.
If a person has not received the teaching of the Scriptures,
if you have not been grounded in the Word of God
or you have not received the promise of the Holy Spirit in your heart,
forcing yourself to do such acts – be healed, be delivered, be saved, in Jesus’ name - is indeed a risk.
Anything that comes by force is not faith.
Force...
Effortless.
If your work of faith is conscious and pretentious, you have not yet learned the lesson of faith.
If you have faith in the finished work of our Lord Jesus Christ,
these acts are spontaneous and unpretentious – natural, without sweat.
Be healed, be delivered - you are not the one doing this, it is God.
The work of healing is not our work.
Healing - it is not our work.
Deliverance - it is not our work.
It is God's work.
When it comes to healing, it is not me.
That is why I can heal you and at the same time give you money because I know that healing is not my work.
Giving you money is a way of receiving a blessing because that healing is not my work.
If I go ahead and give you money to help you, bless you as well, it is a way of receiving a blessing from God.
I cannot say that I healed; I am not the one who is healing.
Don't be surprised if a man of God prays for you and heals you, and at the same time gives you money.
What?
You give me money after my healing?
No, don't be surprised because that healing is not his work.
He is just being used as a "material".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Don't be surprised if man of God prays for you and heals you...
"I am healed" - "You have to pay"
No!
That healing is not his job or work - it is God's work.
If he heals you and gives you money, don't be surprised - he himself is also looking for a blessing.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
It is a way of paying his tithes.
If you have faith in the finished work of our Lord Jesus Christ...
There are many faiths: faith in faith, faith in yourself, faith in a business.
One might say, "I have faith in that job".
That is not the kind of faith we are talking about here.
The kind of faith we are talking about here is a trust.
Faith means a trust.
T R U S T
Don’t try to trust anyone.
Just love everyone; trust only God.
Don’t trust me, just love me.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You can only trust Someone who has no beginning and has no end.
I have a beginning and an end.
Only Jesus has no beginning and has no end – trust Him.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If you have faith in the finished work of our Lord Jesus Christ, that is "by His stripes"...
All what we are looking for - blessing, victories, salvation, or whatever - they are all past issues.
The healing, victory, deliverance - they are past, on the cross.
All the way to Calvary
He went for me
He went to set me free
They are all past events.
You have no reason to be sick, to suffer.
In Him there is nothing like that.
If you have faith in that - that is what I call "finished work"...
If you now have faith in the finished works, these acts are spontaneous and unpretentious - that is natural.
"Be healed!" - it is natural.
It will flow just like that.
You will not be conscious.
You will be under the influence of God.
When people are under the influence of wine; this is where you want to go, isn't it?
This is where you want to go, isn't it?
Why can't you go where you want to go?
Because you are under what? - Influence.
Are you conscious?
[No.]
Oh yes!
If your work of faith is something conscious, you have not yet learned the lesson of faith.
If you are conscious, you will be looking for members of your family to heal them.
You will not pray for your enemies.
"You will see today!"
"Be healed!"
Auntie, come; let me heal you so that you can go and rest.
Because she is my family, because I am conscious of...
The SCOAN Sunday Service
And we are not here for that now.
Just as if someone is under the influence of wine.
When you take "kaka kaka kaka" - how do you call it?
Real "uguguru".
We are not seeing the 'mother one' today.
You can finish ten bottles.
The real one, the local one in those days - just a spoon...
The SCOAN Sunday Service
It is where I want to go, isn't it?
Why I couldn't go there?
Because I am what? - Under the influence.
Under what? - Influence.
And I am not what?
- I am not conscious of what I am doing.
If I were conscious of what I was doing, I would not be going the way I am going
because I am not conscious.
If your work of faith is something conscious, you will be looking for your family to pray for them first.
You will not pray for your enemy.
If your enemy comes for prayer, you will say, "Please, go.
You have forgotten what you have done".
This is what happens today.
We are conscious of ourselves when we are praying.
So, if your work of faith is something conscious and pretentious, you have not learned the lesson of faith.
When you are to pray: "It is 4 o'clock, hello, please, I will call you back" - you want to pray -
you are conscious of what you are doing.
Prayer is not your work.
Or, "Prayer is the key, prayer is the key" - you are praying in your room.
Somebody knocks on the door - you say, "Wait for me! Let me go and open the door. We are praying.
Come and join us" - you are conscious of what you are doing.
Prayer is not yours.
When you are praying, you don't know you are taken from this tent.
You are no longer in this tent.
See, my brother has this handset when he prays.
If there is any phone call, he stops the prayer and...
And does what?
Off it - it means you are conscious of what you are doing.
When you are conscious of what you are doing,
it means you are using your reasoning, mental power to pray, not the Spirit of God.
You say, "At 3 o'clock, I will break my fast".
How do you know when you will break your fast?
Exactly at 3 o'clock, whatever you will be doing, you will stop it.
You want to break your fasting.
You are conscious of what you are doing.
Reasoning, mental power...
What is the result of this?
If you have faith on these, what will happen is that after prayer,
you will still be worried and full of anxiety as if you have never prayed at all
because your faith is not on the finished works of our Lord, Jesus Christ.
Anytime you have that, you will know - this is what the man of God was saying.
You can know.
If the work of your faith is something conscious, after prayer,
you will still be worried and full of anxiety as if you have never prayed at all.
This shows there is no evidence of faith.
Anytime God gives us faith, He gives us evidence of the faith.
Evidence of the faith is – after prayer, joy.
Prayer for any request must be followed by an absolute trust in God that He is now working out the answer.
Anytime God gives us faith, He gives us evidence of the faith.
What is the evidence of faith?
Evidence of faith is an absolute trust after prayer.
"In Jesus' name, amen!" - now, an absolute trust in Him that He is working out the answer.
Let me tell you - faith does not rely on itself; God is the place where faith rests.
Only those who have such rest have faith.
What is rest?
Rest in God's love, wisdom and power.
He gives us faith and He gives us evidence of the faith.
No matter what you think, feel or do – what God has said is final.
No matter what you feel of think, "This should be this way or that way..."
What you think or feel...
What matters is what God has said; He speaks to us through His Word by His Spirit.
The Holy Spirit intercedes for us.
We don’t know how to pray.
Do you know that?
The Holy Spirit intercedes for us.
We don't know how to pray.
If the Holy Spirit is the One interceding for us because we do not know how to pray,
how can you be conscious of what you are saying?
He is the One who will take you out of this tent when you are praying of Him.
Acts of faith are but acts of self-surrender.
What do I mean?
I mean, putting an absolute stop to your own work, way, thinking, reasoning
and to rest in God's love, wisdom and power.
Putting an absolute stop to your own work, way, thinking, reasoning.
And you want to be...
99% of Christians today - this is our problem.
We have prayer points - it is consciousness.
When I was very little, there was a pastor who used to come to my mum, my late mum.
In those days I was in primary school.
Each time I saw this pastor, I complained, "Oh, this man has come again."
Because we would be on our knees for 5 hours.
Whenever I saw the pastor coming, I would say, "Oh my God".
Sometimes I would even hide myself.
Each prayer point - 30 minutes.
We would be on our knees.
"Prayer for pardon!"
I would finish my own in less than 2 minutes.
I would open my eyes and look around.
I would be looking at everybody who was praying.
They would continue to pray.
There was a time I approached my mum on my knees and I drew my mum's attire.
The attire fell on the ground.
Mummy opened her eyes and said, "Do you want to undress me?"
Indeed, the attire just fell down.
My mum opened her eyes - I said, "Aha, my mum is conscious of what she is doing".
Momma drew back and hit me.
The pastor opened his eyes and said "What happened?
Aha, these people were not calling God.
You people are fighting in the presence of God - it is not God, God is not there".
The pastor said, "Take it easy. Prayer for mercy again".
He started again.
I was looking for something to stop it.
My mummy drew her attire, tied it back and she hit me.
After the prayer she came and said, "You have been very stubborn. What are you doing this for?"
I said, "How can we be using 5 hours on our knees?"
Like I have said,
anything that comes by force is not faith.
Like, what we have seen now.
Acts of faith are but acts of self-surrender.
Let someone say, "Anything that comes by force is not faith."
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Faith is something that comes spontaneously.
Let someone say it.
"Faith is something that comes spontaneously."
Look at my brother.
Can you see?
You see my brother?
I can see you.
You can see me, yes.
OK.
Do I need now to force myself to believe that you are the one...
No.
and begin to do like this?
Not at all.
No, no, no.
That is faith.
Within a second, I believe - that is faith.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Within a second I believe, it is a man.
I do not need to force myself or struggle to believe.
This is what you people are doing today.
This is what you are doing.
Struggle to believe, "Is it the one? Or is it any other person? Who is the man?"
Whereas this is the man.
I can see you are the one.
I don't need to force myself to believe, or struggle to believe.
That is faith for you.
Say after me, "Acts of faith are but of self-surrender."
Again.
[Acts of faith are but of self-surrender.]
Putting an absolute stop to your own way, doing, looking, work
and rest in God's love, wisdom, power – that is faith.
You may be seated, thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You must be under the influence of God to do the will of God.
If I want to do what this man wants me to do, I must be under your influence.
OK, what do you want me to do?
You want me to go there and you want me to follow you?
Let's go.
I must be under his influence to follow him, where he wants to go
because where he wants to go is not where I want to go.
I want to go a different way and he wants to go this way.
Before I surrender, I must be under his influence.
OK, let's go.
Now, it means that out of faith,
out of self-surrender,
I have surrendered to this man.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I surrender all
All to Thee
My blessed Saviour
I surrender all
Unto Jesus I surrender all
All to Jesus I surrender
All to Him I freely give
I will ever live and trust Him
In His presence daily live
I surrender all
All to Thee
My blessed Saviour
I surrender all
Acts of faith are but acts of self-surrender.
Putting an absolute stop to our own way, work, thinking, thoughts
and rest in God's love, wisdom and power.